♪ Lullaby and goodnight ♪
♪ With roses bedight ♪
♪ With lilies o 'er spread ♪
♪ ls baby 's wee bed ♪
♪ Tomorrow morn , if God deems ♪
♪ You will wake from your dreams ♪
Good night .
( Instrumental music continues )
( panting )
( shouts )
You 're it !
One , two , three , four ...
Five !
( Instrumental music playing )
( water sloshing )
( birds chirping )
Lukas ?
( tense music rising )
( water dripping )
( fly buzzing )
( echoing giggle )
11,12 ,
13,14 ,
15,16 ,
17,18 ,
19 , 20 ...
Lukas ?
GOODNIGHT MOMMY
( honks )
( footsteps approaching )
- Mom ? - Mom ?
( blinds closing )
Mom ?
That 's a fine hello .
Look at your clothes .
Filthy . Take them off right now .
Not here !
Undress by the washing machine . And then take a shower .
Move it !
Ow .
( laughing )
There you are .
Thanks .
( inaudible whisper )
Lukas wants some too .
Then he can ask me himself .
You only made supper for me .
You know why .
You should apologize .
Okay .
- Am I a person ? - No .
- Am I a thing ? - Yes .
- Am I a cell phone ? - No .
- Am I a pair of pants ? - No .
- Can you wear me ? - No .
- Can you eat me ? - No .
- Do you need me every day ? - Yes .
Hmm ...
- Am I hair ? - No .
It 's a thing .
That 's needed in daily life .
You use it almost every day .
Do I ?
Not by yourself , but ...
Hmm ...
- A car ? - Yes , right .
You got it .
Okay .
- Am I an animal ? - No .
- Am I a thing ? - No .
Am I a person ?
Yes .
- Am I a man ? - No .
- Am I a woman ? - Yes .
- A grown-up ? - Yes .
Am I still alive ?
Yes .
Am I on TV ?
Am I ...
a TV hostess ?
Yes .
- Am I on German TV ? - No .
Austrian .
Am I famous ?
Well , sort of .
Barbara Karlich ?
No .
( inaudible whisper )
Um ...
A clue ?
You like animals .
Hmm ?
Come on !
You like animals .
Another clue .
You have two kids .
How do I know who has two kids ? Do I know the person ?
Yes .
( crickets chirping )
( owl hooting )
( spits )
( timer ticking )
( timer ringing )
( ticking )
Lukas !
( water running )
( indistinct chatter )
( footsteps approaching )
( sighs )
That 's enough .
Hey !
That 's it .
- Come on ! - Mom !
I have something to say .
We were playing !
I don 't care .
Dad lets us play .
I don 't care what your dad does .
This is important .
I want you to look at me .
- So start already . - Excuse me ?
Nothing .
The doctor said I need rest .
And I expect your support . There 'll be some new rules .
I want absolute quiet in the house .
I have to sleep . If it 's important ,
knock .
And no visitors .
If anyone asks ,
Mom is ill .
We 'll keep the blinds closed .
I have to avoid sunlight .
You 'll play only in the garden , quietly .
Bring nothing inside .
No branches , no animals ...
What are you doing ?
We 'll start over .
Right ?
We need to hold this family together .
One from me and one from Lukas .
Very nice .
I 'm serious about what I just said .
We won 't forget , right ?
Good .
It 's bedtime now .
Good night .
( door closes )
( rustling )
( inaudible whispering )
- She 's so different . - Well ...
It 's just the operation .
You think ?
Yeah .
I don 't know .
How would you feel
if you 'd had an operation like that ?
I don 't know .
She s not like our mom .
Play it again .
[ woman ] I 'm giving you lots and lots of kisses .
( kissing )
I can 't wait until I 'm back .
Pull the covers up and close your eyes .
♪ Can you count the stars that brightly ♪
♪ Twinkle in the midnight sky ? ♪
♪ Can you count the clouds , so lightly ♪
♪ O 'er the meadows floating by ? ♪
♪ God , the Lord , doth mark their number ♪
♪ With His eyes that never slumber ♪
♪ You He sees and you He loves ♪
Good night .
( clattering )
( creaking )
( door closes )
( panting )
( thunder rumbling )
( laughing )
( belches )
( laughs )
( both belching )
( belching and laughter continue )
( doorbell rings )
( footsteps approaching )
Get Mom .
Mom ?
( door closes )
( crunching )
Lukas ?
( clattering )
- Hello ? - Hi , good morning .
You sure placed a killer order . So much , all at once .
- Someone having a party ? - No .
Who 's all this pizza for ?
Pepperoni , pepperoni ? Is that your favorite ?
Pepperoni pizza . You must love it .
Yeah .
Bought enough for a year .
There we go , it 's all in there .
( tense music rising )
( animal whimpering )
( whimpering )
( purring )
( door opens )
( door closes )
( footsteps approaching )
( jar opens )
( knocking loudly )
Open up .
What in hell ...
Since when do we lock doors ?
Sorry .
( clattering )
Why is there a lighter in here ?
I wanted to burn some books .
Don 't act smart .
( clattering )
( grunts )
Mama !
Get off !
Let him go !
( crickets chirping )
( footsteps departing )
( tense music rising )
( gasps )
( hissing )
( door opens )
( footsteps approaching )
( piano playing Lullaby and Good Night )
( spraying )
( footsteps approaching )
OUR WEDDING
( typing )
INGRID ULRICH REAL ESTATE - METTLER HOUSE
FOR SALE : STYLISH RETREAT , PRICE ON REQUEST
( knock at door )
( beep )
( footsteps approaching )
( door opens )
( clattering )
( door closes )
( knocks )
( door opens )
( door closes )
( static )
Lukas !
Leo ?
Time for your chores !
( Phone rings )
( indistinct chatter )
( turns off vacuum )
I 've other worries .
I won 't play along anymore .
I have to make him stop . He has to face it .
Wait a second , sorry .
( turns on vacuum )
( door locks )
Not here either .
Leo ?
Lukas , look .
What 's wrong with him ?
Leo ?
I 'm sure it was Mom .
( Hissing )
( footsteps approaching )
( footsteps departing )
Well ?
Fine .
Are you crazy ?
Stop that .
What 's going on ?
What is going on ?
- We want our mom back . - What ?
We want our mom back .
Have you gone crazy ?
Are you out of your mind ?
Clean this up and go to your room !
You 're not our mom .
To your room !
Show us your birthmark .
- Enough ! - Show us your birthmark .
I 've had it .
Anything else , maybe ?
( Door slams )
I want you to say 10 times that I 'm your mother .
- Open up ! - Say it .
- You 're my mom . - Properly .
You 're my mom .
Look at me .
You 're my mom , you 're my mom ...
Louder .
You 're my mom .
You 're my mom . You 're my mom .
Stop this foolishness !
I 'm not playing along anymore . Understand ?
There 'll be only one breakfast and one set of clothes .
And promise me not to talk to your brother !
No .
( slap )
Promise me .
I 'm going to get so mad ! Promise me !
Give me your cell . Now !
( clattering )
Stay in your room !
( crying )
She wants to tear us apart .
Does that hurt ?
Mm-mm .
- Does that hurt ? - No .
Does that hurt ?
Mm-mm .
( footsteps approaching )
( door unlocking )
( beep )
( static )
Mom , please come back .
I 'll do anything you want .
Please come back .
All I wish for is that you 'll come back to us .
( liquid pouring )
( static )
( timer ticking )
( timer ringing )
Elias ?
( ticking )
( tense music rising )
( static )
( heavy breathing )
( beep )
Trim around your ear .
Here ?
Yeah .
Better ?
Now we look the same .
Now she won 't be able to tell us apart .
( door unlocking )
( knock at door )
It 's me . Open the door .
Are we friends ?
I 'm not mad anymore .
Please open the door .
Well ?
Are we friends again ?
Hmm ?
I have something .
Thanks .
- Great , huh ? - Yes .
Can we go outside and try it ?
Hey ! Hey !
( tense music rising )
( man playing accordion and shouting indistinctly )
Yes ?
Um ...
What is it ?
Can you help us ?
Yes .
What 's it about ?
( inaudible whisper )
- Are you the priest ? - No , I 'm the sexton .
Where 's the priest ?
He 's not here .
( inaudible whisper )
- Can we call him ? - Yeah .
Sure you can .
Can you come inside the police station with us ?
And talk to the policeman
and explain it to him ?
Yeah , no problem .
( thunder rumbles )
( engine turns off )
( door opens )
( door closes )
[ man ] Hey !
( thunder rumbles )
Open up !
Come out of there ! Come out !
Thank you .
Would you like to explain ?
It was all a bit much .
The accident . The separation .
( thunder rumbles )
( locks door )
( door locks )
( wrapper crinkling )
( sniffles )
( thunder rumbles )
( keys jingling )
( blinds opening )
( clanging )
What 's going on ?
Huh ?
Where is our mom ?
I 'm going insane . Insane .
How do I get up ?
You don 't .
Where is our mom ?
Lukas said , " Where is our mom ? "
Untie me now .
No .
It hurts . Untie me .
Tell us where our mom is .
I 'm your mom !
No .
Who 's she ?
Hmm ?
Where are the scissors ?
Who is she ?
Hmm ?
A friend .
We always dressed the same .
Who is she really ?
( phone buzzing )
Answer .
Please answer .
( door unlocking )
( blinds opening )
Hi , I 'm from Vienna .
What should I say ? It 's my first time doing this .
I like to cook , watch movies .
But I also enjoy spending the evening watching TV .
( strikes key )
Look .
( grunts )
Go away !
Help me .
( grunts )
Ow ! Ow ! Ow !
Stop it !
Stop !
- I don 't see it . - What are you doing ?
Take another look .
What is this ? What is this ?
- In the video your eyes are brown . - What ?
They 're contacts , Christ ! They 're in the bathroom .
( sighs )
( door opens )
Why are you lying to me ?
I thought we agreed not to believe her .
So ? I changed my mind .
Do you believe her , you retard ?
You 're the retard !
( grunts )
( grunting )
Help !
( clattering )
Where are the damn scissors ?
Do you understand ? Get the scissors !
( spits )
( coughs )
Lukas ?
Elias ...
Sit beside me . Come on .
Come , Elias . Sit here .
Come sit beside me , Elias .
Come on , sit down . So we can talk .
Look .
Elias ...
You know I 'm your mom .
Hmm ?
( sighs )
I can 't untie myself .
Just go to the bathroom , get the scissors and cut me loose .
Nothing bad has happened . Cut me loose .
I want you to say 10 times , " I won 't listen to my brother . "
I won 't listen to my brother . I won 't ...
Louder , please .
I won 't listen to my brother . I won 't listen ...
I said louder .
Our mom wouldn 't do that .
More clearly .
Elias ...
I 'm sorry .
Again .
I 'm sorry , Elias .
( turns off video )
Come now .
Please . Cut me loose .
What happened to your nose ?
Nothing . Nothing serious .
There , you see ?
You 'll cut me loose
and I 'll make you breakfast .
Cut my feet loose , they hurt .
Lukas ?
I know it 's hard , but we 'll make it .
Come , just cut my feet loose .
Come on , it 'll take a sec . I 'll make breakfast .
Just cut it .
That 's it .
What are you doing ?
There .
What ?
What is it ?
Stop .
They had to remove it in hospital .
They 're dangerous .
Liar !
They had to . They had no ...
Admit that it 's a lie .
Just cut me loose , please .
( footsteps departing )
Stop .
Stop !
( grunting )
( whimpering )
Ow !
( crying )
Tell us where our mom is .
Tell us where our mom is !
( crying )
( screams )
( tense music rising )
( cutting tape )
( whimpers )
( door opens )
( door closes )
( peaceful music playing )
( doorbell rings )
( knock at door )
[ man ] It 's open .
Hello , Red Cross !
( muffled screams )
Hello ?
Red Cross . Care to make a donation ?
( knocking )
Is anybody home ?
I 'll have a look .
Hello ?
( knocking )
Red Cross .
( muffled screams )
Nobody 's there .
It was unlocked , someone must be home .
( muffled screams )
Hello ?
Maybe they 're upstairs .
( muffled screams )
[ woman ] Hello ?
Red Cross .
( muffled screams )
- Hello ? - Hello !
Hello .
Is your mom home ?
No , she 's not home .
Not upstairs ? We heard something .
No , that 's our dog .
- She 's not home ? - No .
It 's our dog .
Uh-huh .
When will Mom be back ?
Hmm ?
Um ...
She 'll be home soon .
Can we wait ?
Where should we wait ?
Hand me the list . I 'll see how much we 've collected .
- The money too ? - Yeah , I 'll count it .
Okay .
- Really bad handwriting . - Yeah .
You 'd swear a doctor had written it .
It 's barely legible .
Looking forward to school ?
- Well ... - It starts soon .
- Where did you go to school before ? - In Vienna .
A lot more going on there .
We 've already collected a tidy sum .
If somebody else gives as much as him ,
we 'll have done pretty well .
Mm-hmm .
We 'll see how much more we get .
What do you do all day ?
Not much .
I have to go to the toilet .
( indistinct chatter )
( chatter continues )
- Uh-huh . - Uh-huh .
Is your mom back ?
Not yet .
Is that your own money ?
No .
- Will your mom be OK with this ? - Yes , I 'm sure she will .
She always gives that much .
We don 't want any trouble .
You realize that ...
We usually don 't accept money from children .
That 's a lot of money .
No , we 're allowed .
Well , it is a nice house . Just look .
I guess they can afford it .
( whimpering )
( blowing )
As a thank-you for the donation ,
here 's a Band-Aid .
( Blows )
Help !
Help ! Help !
Help ! Help ! Help !
Help !
Stop ! Stop !
( whimpering )
( muffled scream )
( crying )
( static )
( microwave oven running )
( beeping )
( whimpering )
( inaudible whisper )
( screaming )
( crying )
( whimpering )
Please prove you 're our mom .
Ask her what my favorite song is .
What 's Lukas ' favorite song ?
Lullaby and Good Night ?
Don 't !
( muffled scream )
♪ Can you count the stars that brightly ♪
♪ Twinkle in the midnight sky ? ♪
♪ Can you count the clouds , so lightly ♪
♪ O 'er the meadows floating by ? ♪
♪ God , the Lord , doth mark their number ♪
♪ With His eyes that never slumber ♪
♪ You He sees and you He loves ♪
( gasps )
( whimpers )
( ticking )
( coughs )
Where 's our mom ?
( timer ringing )
( grunting )
( whimpering )
( gagging )
( screaming )
( whimpering )
( gagging )
Don 't you know when you have to pee ?
We 're not changing them .
Hello ?
Untie me .
Now change the bed .
Take off the sheets .
Come on , take them off .
( groans )
( grunts )
( tense music rising )
( footsteps approaching )
( gasps )
( whimpering )
( sighs )
Elias ?
Where 's our mom ?
Elias , come here .
Where is she ?
Fine .
Elias , let 's make a deal .
I 'll play along again .
I 'll talk to Lukas again .
Lukas will be alive .
I 'll make you both breakfast ,
put out your clothes . We 'll do things , like before .
But you have to believe me
that I 'm your mom .
You won 't really do that .
I promise .
Elias ...
It 's not your fault Lukas died .
The accident wasn 't your fault .
Do you really believe her ?
Hmm ? Hmm ?
She 's lying .
Let her prove she 's our mom .
What am I doing ?
What 's Lukas doing ?
But I can 't see him !
What 's he doing ?
Elias ...
Mom would know that .
Mom could see him .
She 'd know what he 's doing .
No , Elias . Don 't !
Elias , don 't !
Elias , do you hear me ?
Elias !
Elias ! Elias ! Elias ! Elias !
Elias ! Elias !
Elias !
Help ! Help !
Elias ! Elias ! Elias ! Elias !
Elias !
( tense music rising )
( Elias humming Lullaby and Good Night )
( continues humming )
( singing )
♪ God , the Lord , doth mark their number ♪
♪ With His eyes that never slumber ♪
♪ You He sees and you He loves ♪
♪ ♪